# Claude Bejjani

## Senior Web Developer

Sin el Fil - Jisr el Wate - Beirut Lebanon

tel: +961 03-48 63 63

Email: <a href="mailto:com/cbejjani@gmail.com">cbejjani@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn

## **Objectives**

Goal-oriented Senior Web Developer brings strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web technologies packages to develop custom-crafted, customer-focused solutions and applications. Committed to high standards of user experience, usability and speed over more than 14 years for multiple users.

## **Experience**

## Aimtech (Remote - Armenia) - Senior Full-Stack Developer

Jan 2021 - Feb 2023

Developed and maintained backend systems using Laravel PHP framework.

Worked on integrating third-party APIs to improve system functionality.

Collaborated with frontend developers to ensure seamless integration with the frontend.

Conducted code reviews and testing to ensure code quality and system reliability.

Tech used: Laravel, Plain PHP, MySql, NodeJs, ReactJs, NextJs, TS, TailwindCSS

Example Project: Solumina for manufacturing (an Intranet local Web Solution) by ibaset.com

## Intuitions (Remote/Hybrid) - Full-Stack Developer

Feb 2020 - Dec 2021

Worked on developing and maintaining WordPress custom plugins and themes.

Implemented custom functionalities using WordPress hooks and filters.

Worked on integrating third-party APIs to enhance system functionality and to feed mobile apps.

Conducted code reviews and testing to ensure code quality and system reliability.

Tech used: Laravel 7, MySql, ReactJS, NextJS, TailwindCSS, WooCommerce, WordPress, GraphQL, Directus CMS.

Example projects: https://cookwithsousou.com, https://barcloud.com/, mefs.vercel.app

### Paravision - Full-Stack Developer

Jun 2014 - Nov 2020

Worked on developing and maintaining backend systems using Laravel PHP framework.

Designed and developed RESTful APIs for various applications.

Worked on integrating various payment gateways to the system.

Conducted code reviews and testing to ensure code quality and system reliability.

Tech used: Laravel, plain PHP/MySQL, WordPress, WooCommerce, Drupal, Bootstrap, JavaScript, CSS

Example projects: touristtube.com - boccard.fr plus a bunch of custom made backends

## Claude Bejjani

## **Senior Web Developer**

Sin el Fil - Jisr el Wate - Beirut Lebanon

tel: <u>+961 03-48 63 63</u>

Email: cbejjani@gmail.com

**LinkedIn** 

### Dowgroup - Full-Stack developer

Mar 2010 - Mai 2014

Developed functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity. Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement. Established presentation consistency across Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces. Implemented website maintenance, content management, update and security resource tutorials to assist end-user training.

Tech used: Drupal CMS, WordPress

Example projects: <u>icldc.ae</u> - <u>unimarcorp.com</u>

## Ebiz Production - PHP - WordPress Developer

Sep 2006 - Oct 2010

Employed search engine optimization tactics to increase reach of targeted audience.

Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.

CSS and HTML W3C standards validation.

Tech used: Plain PHP with Pear library, Wordpress, HTML CSS, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON

Example projects: <u>turquoise-voyages.fr</u> - <u>elior-services.fr</u>

#### **Education**

#### 2005-2006 NEW HORIZON – (MICROSOFT)

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED APPLICATION DEVELOPER,

Completed the full track of Microsoft application developer

## DIPLÔME UNIVERSITAIRE DE TECHNOLOGIE, (KAFAAT UNIVERSITY)

Succeeded with 93/100 grades

#### Communication

English: Professional - French: Good - Arabic: Good

#### **Hobbies**

Knowing that I am a very good team player, I would like to sit alone, watching the sunset and nature's beauty. I am a piano player, love to cook and I am a Qualified Personal Trainer.